Omar J. López G.

Frontend Developer / JS developer

Bogotá, Colombia (+57) 322 3038917 omarjlg1893@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a highly experienced frontend developer with over 7 years of experience in the field of web development. My specialty is frontend development, with expertise in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and experience working with frameworks such as React, Angular and Vue. I have primarily worked on B2B applications, internal management systems for startups, and website redesigns for businesses.

I have experience working with Agile methodologies such as Scrum and Kanban, and have used tools such as Git for version control and JIRA for project management. In addition to my technical skills, I possess valuable soft skills such as adaptability and a desire to continuously learn and grow. I am a flexible professional who can adapt to different environments and projects, with a growth mindset that drives me to continuously seek new opportunities to improve my IT skills and knowledge.

EXPERIENCE

Huge Inc, Bogotá - Colombia — Frontend Developer

MARCH 2021 - MARCH 2023.

I worked for the redesign of the web design of two companies such as Northern Trust (Banking) and Abbvie (Health). In both projects, I was involved in web accessibility development . Using tools like React, VanillaJS and VueJS. Also performed unit testing and used methodologies such as Scrum.

Rappi, Bogotá - Colombia — Frontend Developer

JULY 2019 - MARCH 2021.

First job in Bogota, Colombia. I worked on several web applications for internal use of the company, using frameworks like React, Angular 2+ and Vue.JS demonstrating a good level of adaptability to changes that may arise. Also worked in the creation of unit tests, with tools like Jest, Enzyme, react-testing-library, Karma, TestBed, Jasmine. Scrum methodology was used.

Momentum Lab, Puerto Ordaz, VE— Frontend Developer

MARCH 2017 - JUNE 2019.

I performed as a frontend developer, in web applications and hybrid applications. With technologies like angular 2+ and ionic 2. I also worked on my first application made with VanillaJS, in code maintenance. And developed under the SCRUM methodology.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

React, Gatsby, Next.JS

Redux, Redux-Thunk

GraphQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDb

AngularJS, Angular 2/4.

Vue.js

Vanilla IS

Ionic, Electron.

SASS, POSTCSS. TailwindCSS

Node, Express, NestJS, Ruby Git

INTERESTING LINKS

Platzi Certificates

Personal Repo

Linkedin

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)

English (B2)

Jam Tech, C.A, Puerto Ordaz, VE — Frontend Developer

FEBRUARY 2016 - MARCH 2017

First job as a Frontend Developer. Mostly worked on hybrid apps using technologies such as AngularJS, Angular 2, Ionic 1 and 2. Performed as a Project Manager in the project "Menú Para Hoy".

EDUCATION

Universidad Gran Mariscal de Ayacucho, Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela — *Systems Engineer*

OCTOBER 2010 - JULY 2016